<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Channel on XeroLinux HQ</title>
    <link>https://xerolinux.xyz/tags/channel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Channel on XeroLinux HQ</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Proudly made in Lebanon &lt;img src=&#39;https://xerolinux.xyz/logos/lb.png&#39; alt=&#39;🇱🇧&#39; width=&#39;18&#39; height=&#39;18&#39; style=&#39;margin: 0; display: inline; vertical-align: middle;&#39;&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://xerolinux.xyz/tags/channel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>XeroLinux YouTube</title>
      <link>https://xerolinux.xyz/news/youtube-status/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xerolinux.xyz/news/youtube-status/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I bring you a different kind of post. So sit back, grab a cup of tea/coffee and read on. It&amp;rsquo;s under this category coz it simply isn&amp;rsquo;t related to Linux.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Back Story 
    &lt;div id=&#34;back-story&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to talk about project&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/strong&gt;. I know I talked about it a few times before, but this time it&amp;rsquo;s not personal. Far from it, it&amp;rsquo;s just to update everyone on the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s begin with how it all started. As I was working on the now discontinued &lt;strong&gt;XeroLinux&lt;/strong&gt; Distro, someone asked me if I could create a channel where I documented everything. At first I hesitated, due to the lack of knowledge there, and being camera shy, which am not anymore as you saw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First few videos did not have my face, but slowly I started to appear in a few until it became the norm. I kept experimenting with a few setups still did until today. Was never satisfied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did not know what type of content to bring you guys, and getting monetization status was hard, until I met Alex from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@thelinuxtube/videos&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TheLinuxTube&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; channel, who introduned me to someone who helped me get there and fast. But sadly, even with that status, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t getting enough views to profit from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get it, it&amp;rsquo;s not your fault, but it was more related to the type of content I was making, mostly related to &lt;strong&gt;ArchLinux&lt;/strong&gt; and my project. I even attempted to to host a podcast, and interview well-known Content Creators, which I failed miserably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did that for a while, then stopped. I came back for a while, thinking that&amp;rsquo;s it am on a roll now, with a video every Wednesday, and a Live at the end of every month. But alas, that did not work in my favor as much as I wanted it to&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Present &amp;amp; Future 
    &lt;div id=&#34;present--future&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which brings me to the present. You will no longer see any videos from me for now. That&amp;rsquo;s it, I do apologize for that. It&amp;rsquo;s also that creating videos has affected my mental health negatively for little gain and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to recover from that. Fear not though, channel isn&amp;rsquo;t going anywhere, I will be leaving it up, in case you find a video that helps you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the future of the channel, well I do not know. Maybe one day, if and when I settle down, with a decent job that actually makes me money to grab the required equipment, take care of some lingering health/appearance issues, I might consider coming back.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Blogging 
    &lt;div id=&#34;blogging&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you might have noticed, lately I have been concentrating on written content. It brings me more joy, more freedom to express myself, and most importantly I get to share more tools and guides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing you will not see from me are Distro Reviews, Vs and Bechmarking posts. Why ? Well quite simply because I lack the tools, hardware for benchmarking, and prefer not to start dramas when it comes to Distro Reviews and Vs posts, because as I have noticed lately, the &lt;strong&gt;FOSS&lt;/strong&gt; community tends to be strongly opinionated, and sees &lt;em&gt;Favoritism&lt;/em&gt; where there is none. I will leave those kinds of posts to those who like to do them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also I think that written content tends to be more useful than videos, simply because in case of commands to be run, paths to be used etc, it&amp;rsquo;s easier to copy and paste rather than pause the video and type them manually. That&amp;rsquo;s not to say that videos are not useful, on the contrary, if it weren&amp;rsquo;t for them, posts would be stale and boring, that&amp;rsquo;s why in my humble opinion, they compliment written content, helping us include a showcase of the product we are talking about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, from now on, and for the foreseeable future I will be concentrating on what I love most, which is blogging. I have so much to share, so little time as the saying goes lol&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;The other blog 
    &lt;div id=&#34;the-other-blog&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, I forgot to mention the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.xerolinux.xyz&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other Blog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, well, since am enjoying written content, I thought I would also start a personal &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt;, where I document how I feel about different things in the land of &lt;strong&gt;FOSS&lt;/strong&gt; and my projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I keep it separate from this site, so as to not litter it with personal feelings as it were. That kind of content has no place here. I made it publicly available, so you can join me on my quest so to say. If you don&amp;rsquo;t care for that kind of content, by all means don&amp;rsquo;t go there. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of lows with a bit of highs.. Simply coz that&amp;rsquo;s how I feel right now. Hoping for more positivity in the near future- (knock on wood).&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Closing words 
    &lt;div id=&#34;closing-words&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know this might be a lot to take in. I just felt like sharing an update regarding the channel, and by extension the present and future state of affairs here at the &lt;strong&gt;XeroLinux HQ&lt;/strong&gt;. I hope I did not bore you to death lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anywho, thanks for reading all this, looking forward to your thoughts on the matter over on &lt;a href=&#34;https://fosstodon.org/@XeroLinux&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fosstodon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://xerolinux.xyz/news/youtube-status/featured.webp" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
