<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>XeroLinux on XeroLinux HQ</title>
    <link>https://xerolinux.xyz/tags/xerolinux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in XeroLinux on XeroLinux HQ</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Proudly made in Lebanon &lt;img src=&#39;https://xerolinux.xyz/logos/lb.png&#39; alt=&#39;🇱🇧&#39; width=&#39;18&#39; height=&#39;18&#39; style=&#39;margin: 0; display: inline; vertical-align: middle;&#39;&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://xerolinux.xyz/tags/xerolinux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Help Needed</title>
      <link>https://xerolinux.xyz/news/help-needed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xerolinux.xyz/news/help-needed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey there&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a new type of post. Please read on to understand what it&amp;rsquo;s all about. &lt;strong&gt;XeroLinux&lt;/strong&gt; urgently needs your help.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Designers needed 
    &lt;div id=&#34;designers-needed&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We here, at the &lt;strong&gt;XeroLinux HQ&lt;/strong&gt; are looking for designers who will help us bring life to our upcoming &lt;strong&gt;Merch Store&lt;/strong&gt;. Yes, you read this right, we are looking to expand our portfolio, adding cool merch that everyone can purchase, as an alternative or additional way to support the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am no designer, nor do I have a high quality logo to start with, just a very low quality one, maybe it can be used for inspiration. Also I am not looking at offering every type of item under the sun, just a few that might be interesting to the &lt;strong&gt;FOSS&lt;/strong&gt; oriented crowd.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Service Chosen 
    &lt;div id=&#34;service-chosen&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The service I have chosen is &lt;a href=&#34;https://fourthwall.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FourthWall&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. I chose this one because Matt from &lt;a href=&#34;https://thelinuxcast.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TheLinuxCast&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; recommended it, and I trust his choice. I am new to all this, so I have &lt;strong&gt;NO&lt;/strong&gt; idea what am doing. That&amp;rsquo;s why your help is needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/Ho4o9GK.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34; /&gt;
    
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have already set up the domain, and added a few basic items with my logo, so now all that&amp;rsquo;s missing is more high quality merch lol. However it&amp;rsquo;s a good start I guess. So if you can help add more and have some cool FOSS meme ideas we can print, let me know.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Compensation 
    &lt;div id=&#34;compensation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, since I am based in Lebanon, it will be very difficult for me to compensate you directly for any services rendered. However we can always reach some sort of understading. We will dicuss this behind the scenes.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Wrapping up 
    &lt;div id=&#34;wrapping-up&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now that you know what I am looking for, and are interested, feel free to contact me either on &lt;a href=&#34;https://fosstodon.org/@XeroLinux&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fosstodon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or by emailing me directly via this &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:techxero@vivaldi.net?subject=XeroLinux%20Merch%20Design&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;E-mail&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. I am looking forward to our collab should it happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://xerolinux.xyz/news/help-needed/featured.webp" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XeroLinux YouTube</title>
      <link>https://xerolinux.xyz/news/youtube-status/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xerolinux.xyz/news/youtube-status/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I bring you a different kind of post. So sit back, grab a cup of tea/coffee and read on. It&amp;rsquo;s under this category coz it simply isn&amp;rsquo;t related to Linux.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Back Story 
    &lt;div id=&#34;back-story&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to talk about project&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/strong&gt;. I know I talked about it a few times before, but this time it&amp;rsquo;s not personal. Far from it, it&amp;rsquo;s just to update everyone on the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s begin with how it all started. As I was working on the now discontinued &lt;strong&gt;XeroLinux&lt;/strong&gt; Distro, someone asked me if I could create a channel where I documented everything. At first I hesitated, due to the lack of knowledge there, and being camera shy, which am not anymore as you saw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First few videos did not have my face, but slowly I started to appear in a few until it became the norm. I kept experimenting with a few setups still did until today. Was never satisfied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did not know what type of content to bring you guys, and getting monetization status was hard, until I met Alex from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@thelinuxtube/videos&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TheLinuxTube&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; channel, who introduned me to someone who helped me get there and fast. But sadly, even with that status, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t getting enough views to profit from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get it, it&amp;rsquo;s not your fault, but it was more related to the type of content I was making, mostly related to &lt;strong&gt;ArchLinux&lt;/strong&gt; and my project. I even attempted to to host a podcast, and interview well-known Content Creators, which I failed miserably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did that for a while, then stopped. I came back for a while, thinking that&amp;rsquo;s it am on a roll now, with a video every Wednesday, and a Live at the end of every month. But alas, that did not work in my favor as much as I wanted it to&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Present &amp;amp; Future 
    &lt;div id=&#34;present--future&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which brings me to the present. You will no longer see any videos from me for now. That&amp;rsquo;s it, I do apologize for that. It&amp;rsquo;s also that creating videos has affected my mental health negatively for little gain and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to recover from that. Fear not though, channel isn&amp;rsquo;t going anywhere, I will be leaving it up, in case you find a video that helps you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the future of the channel, well I do not know. Maybe one day, if and when I settle down, with a decent job that actually makes me money to grab the required equipment, take care of some lingering health/appearance issues, I might consider coming back.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Blogging 
    &lt;div id=&#34;blogging&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you might have noticed, lately I have been concentrating on written content. It brings me more joy, more freedom to express myself, and most importantly I get to share more tools and guides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing you will not see from me are Distro Reviews, Vs and Bechmarking posts. Why ? Well quite simply because I lack the tools, hardware for benchmarking, and prefer not to start dramas when it comes to Distro Reviews and Vs posts, because as I have noticed lately, the &lt;strong&gt;FOSS&lt;/strong&gt; community tends to be strongly opinionated, and sees &lt;em&gt;Favoritism&lt;/em&gt; where there is none. I will leave those kinds of posts to those who like to do them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also I think that written content tends to be more useful than videos, simply because in case of commands to be run, paths to be used etc, it&amp;rsquo;s easier to copy and paste rather than pause the video and type them manually. That&amp;rsquo;s not to say that videos are not useful, on the contrary, if it weren&amp;rsquo;t for them, posts would be stale and boring, that&amp;rsquo;s why in my humble opinion, they compliment written content, helping us include a showcase of the product we are talking about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, from now on, and for the foreseeable future I will be concentrating on what I love most, which is blogging. I have so much to share, so little time as the saying goes lol&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;The other blog 
    &lt;div id=&#34;the-other-blog&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, I forgot to mention the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.xerolinux.xyz&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other Blog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, well, since am enjoying written content, I thought I would also start a personal &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt;, where I document how I feel about different things in the land of &lt;strong&gt;FOSS&lt;/strong&gt; and my projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I keep it separate from this site, so as to not litter it with personal feelings as it were. That kind of content has no place here. I made it publicly available, so you can join me on my quest so to say. If you don&amp;rsquo;t care for that kind of content, by all means don&amp;rsquo;t go there. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of lows with a bit of highs.. Simply coz that&amp;rsquo;s how I feel right now. Hoping for more positivity in the near future- (knock on wood).&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Closing words 
    &lt;div id=&#34;closing-words&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know this might be a lot to take in. I just felt like sharing an update regarding the channel, and by extension the present and future state of affairs here at the &lt;strong&gt;XeroLinux HQ&lt;/strong&gt;. I hope I did not bore you to death lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anywho, thanks for reading all this, looking forward to your thoughts on the matter over on &lt;a href=&#34;https://fosstodon.org/@XeroLinux&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fosstodon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://xerolinux.xyz/news/youtube-status/featured.webp" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add XeroLinux Repo</title>
      <link>https://xerolinux.xyz/news/add-our-repo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xerolinux.xyz/news/add-our-repo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey there&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was recently asked if my Repo can be added to other Arch-Based Distros, short answer is yes of course you can. I will be showing you how below. Just note that my repo usually contains stuff I deem necessary, but in case you find some stuff that can be useful to you on ArchLinux feel free to add it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run below command :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;Bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; -e &lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;\n[xerolinux]\nSigLevel = Optional TrustAll\nServer = https://repos.xerolinux.xyz/$repo/$arch&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; sudo tee -a /etc/pacman.conf
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s basically it, now update database with &lt;code&gt;sudo pacman -Syyu&lt;/code&gt; and you will notice my repo part of the update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers :heart:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://xerolinux.xyz/news/add-our-repo/featured.webp" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Submit Site Content</title>
      <link>https://xerolinux.xyz/news/submit-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xerolinux.xyz/news/submit-content/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Intro 
    &lt;div id=&#34;intro&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I was thinking, why be the only one submitting content for the site ? This site is now a place to post &lt;strong&gt;Linux&lt;/strong&gt; news, guides, and tools among other stuff. It&amp;rsquo;s all for sharing our love for &lt;strong&gt;FOSS&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;How to create content 
    &lt;div id=&#34;how-to-create-content&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you feel like doing a write up that you think would be useful to others, you can do that, and guess what, it&amp;rsquo;s super easy&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s just a single &lt;em&gt;markdown&lt;/em&gt; file called &lt;code&gt;index.md&lt;/code&gt; which contains the text and an image called &lt;code&gt;featured.png&lt;/code&gt; inside a folder named &lt;code&gt;post-title&lt;/code&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s it ! Once that&amp;rsquo;s done you zip them n send my way when I will go through it clean it up n publish&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;- Folder contents&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/nBUbAZg.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image1&#34; /&gt;
    
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;- Markdown contents&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/sdCCPtn.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image2&#34; /&gt;
    
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to update the date of the post in &lt;code&gt;date:&lt;/code&gt;, also give it a short descriptive &lt;code&gt;title:&lt;/code&gt; with a good &lt;code&gt;description&lt;/code&gt;. Finally use the right &lt;code&gt;tags:&lt;/code&gt; as shown in the screenshot. If in doubt click this  to check &amp;raquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/xerolinux/XeroHub/tree/main/content/posts/spotube-for-spotify&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Template&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that out of the way, for more information about the various supported &lt;strong&gt;Shortcodes&lt;/strong&gt; you can use, you can find them here &amp;raquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://blowfish.page/docs/shortcodes/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BlowFish Shortcodes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks again &amp;amp; Cheers :heart:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://xerolinux.xyz/news/submit-content/featured.webp" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fresh New Look</title>
      <link>https://xerolinux.xyz/news/new-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xerolinux.xyz/news/new-site/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Not Again ! 
    &lt;div id=&#34;not-again-&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yep, again lol&amp;hellip; I dunno what else to say. I will keep trying different designs out until I am satisfied. But if all goes well, this will be the last time, who knows ? FOr now enjoy the new look n feel. I really hope you like it. I need to thank &lt;a href=&#34;https://zaney.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zaney&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for letting me know about this awesome theme. I am still figuring it out as I go. If you can help feel free to let me know.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;What is it ? 
    &lt;div id=&#34;what-is-it-&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, if you do not know, this site is using &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hugo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; with a theme called &lt;a href=&#34;https://blowfish.page&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blowfish&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Great combo if you ask me. So many features to go through. I did not even scratch the surface yet. Things will get better soon.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;What about your other blog ? 
    &lt;div id=&#34;what-about-your-other-blog-&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s a tricky question. Consider the other blog as my journal, where I post my thoughts and feelings about things that are happening in the &lt;strong&gt;FOSS&lt;/strong&gt; world. Here I will be posting updates related to my various projects, as well as some other &lt;strong&gt;Open Source&lt;/strong&gt; news/articles.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;And the Forum ? 
    &lt;div id=&#34;and-the-forum-&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The XeroLinux &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.xerolinux.xyz&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forums&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; will be closed down by the end of this month once I have ported over all releveant posts from it. So do not be surprised if you come looking and you don&amp;rsquo;t find them.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Closing words 
    &lt;div id=&#34;closing-words&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know this might be a lot to take in. I am trying to organize things to the best of my abilities. I will be putting everything under one roof, this one. My &amp;ldquo;Journal&amp;rdquo; however will remain coz I do not want to tarnish this site with my ramblings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until then let me know what you think of this new look. If you have any suggestions or ideas on how I can make it all better feel free to let me know how. Thanks for reading this. Here&amp;rsquo;s to future posts&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers :heart:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://xerolinux.xyz/news/new-site/featured.webp" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
